Suchitra Srinath

HR Business Partner - Accenture Operations, APAC at Accenture

Summary

I am a Senior HR professional and goal driven management executive with distinctive experience of over 17 years' in well-known conglomerates namely Accenture and IBM. Leveraging my functional experience in talent strategy/management, strategic HR operations, service delivery, process management and program development/implementation, I have had documented success in delivering original, results focused, and astute solutions to address global and local HR challenges.

Experience

HR Business Partner - Accenture Operations, APAC at Accenture

September 2015 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Develop and deliver Human Capital Strategy and HR results aligned to business objectives of Accenture Operations across APAC. Partner extensively with the business to create strategic talent management programs to improve workforce performance. Provide counsel to leadership on people issues i.e. career planning and leadership development. Define requirements based on business needs, confirm suitability of HR strategy, programs, processes and services and partner with HR groups to ensure relevancy of programs and initiatives and facilitate implementation by providing insights.

Vice President - HR Strategic Initiatives & Programs at Accenture

June 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Responsibilities: Design and develop cutting edge HR strategies and talent initiatives that enable the Organization to build and sustain a world class HR function. In specific, define future ready strategic initiatives and project manage their implementation, establish a framework to enhance visibility of HR's contribution to relevant internal and external stakeholders and implement HR Innovation ecosystem to build the capability to produce innovative HR solutions/programs that benefit the organization and workforce

Vice President - Global Analytics & Business Support at Accenture

August 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Delivered holistic business improvements by establishing quantitative management framework and analytic packages that provided solutions for critical business challenges in the areas of talent hiring, sentiment analytic solutions, impact of learning on organization productivity and predictive attrition, etc. Managed critical HR Service Delivery initiatives across multiple geographies and successfully delivered high level cost efficiency and business impact to the Organization. The portfolio was global providing leadership to a team of 36 erudite professional spread across various countries (majority US & Latin America).

Vice President - HR Service Delivery at Accenture, Philippines

January 2010 - August 2012 (2 years 8 months)

Managed HR Service Delivery for Accenture Philippines, owning enhancing/revamping process and policies across Compensation, Benefits, Employee Data Management, Performance Management, International Assignments, Disciplinary Process, Recruitment, Headcount Management, Employee Relations, Exit Management, etc. With in-depth knowledge of business requirements and recruitment industry best practices, successfully delivered talent & leadership programs, provided directions for maximizing level of productivity. Engaged as a business partner, planned and delivered cost efficiency projects, directing & ensuring positive results during multiple corporate audits and certification. Spearheaded defining and implementing various strategic initiatives and enabled industrialization of multiple HR best practices. Played an active lead role in implementing massive HR transformation initiative.

Dy. General Manager at IBM

August 1997 - December 2009 (12 years 5 months)

I commenced my professional career with IBM and served in various functions progressed very quickly from the lowest career level to a leadership role in HR. In the last stint at IBM, handled the role of Country Head – Business Controls, IBM Daksh Philippines from Jun 2007 to December 2009. I leveraged my skills in establishing & implementing Process Risk & Control Management Processes in India, Philippines and other Asian countries geared towards optimizing and enhancing productivity at HR. In addition, I was rigorously involved in the massive HR transformation project and HR process due diligence of Daksh Acquisition.

Volunteer Experience

Board Member and Volunteer at Computer training for the Blind, Phillippines

Skills & Expertise

Vendor Management

Program Management

Management

Outsourcing

Performance Management

Talent Acquisition

Strategy

Change Management

Employee Relations

Business Analysis

Risk Management

Human Resources

Pavroll

Project Management

Team Management

Recruiting Leadership

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore

EGMP, General Management, 2005 - 2006

University of Mysore

Bachelor of Commerce

Suchitra Srinath

HR Business Partner - Accenture Operations, APAC at Accenture



Contact Suchitra on LinkedIn